Records of the Athletics Department RG.41
New York University Archives
Records of Athletics Programs at New York University
1889-2015
New York University Archives
New York University. Athletics Department
RG.41
211.5 Linear Feet in 190 record cartons, 7 manuscript boxes, 1 half manuscript box, 2 custom boxes, and 11 oversize flat boxes
This collection contains the records of the New York University Athletics Department, including materials related to intercollegiate and intramural teams, player information, newspaper clippings, press releases, photographs, and team rosters and schedules. The collection spans from approximately 1889 to the 2010s.
Conditions Governing Access
Administrative records and unpublished reports of New York University are closed for a period of 20 years from the date of their creation. Access to files spanning multiple years will be opened to researchers based on the date of the most recent materials. Board of Trustees records are closed for 35 years from the date of creation. Materials related to personnel, grievances, job and fellowship searches and applications, and all files that fall under the federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) are permanently restricted. Additional restrictions may apply to other materials in this collection. For questions regarding specific restrictions, please contact the University Archives.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred to the archives in numerous accessions between 2012-2018. The accession numbers associated with this collection are 12.03, 2019.033, 2018.022, 06.029, 15.043, 2016.004, 2016.042, 16.016, and 92.033.
Appraisal
Duplicate pieces of the Bobcat Costume were deaccessioned in February 2019.
Arrangement
The collection is organized by sport, with additional series designated for administrative records, promotional material and records related to NYU athletes who competed in the Olympics.
Historical Note
Athletic competition began at New York University in 1873, when the first intercollegiate games in baseball and football were played. Formal intercollegiate competition did not begin until 1894, when NYU's move to the University Heights campus in the Bronx provided space for a budding athletics program to grow. On that campus the University erected a new gymnasium, as well as football and baseball fields. By 1907 the University fielded varsity baseball, football, basketball, tennis, and track teams.
NYU athletics continued to grow in success and popularity throughout the first half of the 20th century as sports became co-ed. Women's sports such as swimming, tennis and baseball began as informal "co-ed activities" in the 1920s and later became varsity programs. The University also saw a number of its students, coaches, and alumni participate in the Olympics, including Sam Jones, Howard and Ted Cann, Jose and Miguel De Capriles, Byron Dyce, and Carol Heiss.
The University's financial struggles forced the Athletics department to shut down both football and basketball in the 1970s as NYU left its Bronx campus. Athletics at NYU experienced a resurgence in the 1980s with the construction of the Jerome S. Coles Sports Center and the move from Division I to Division III competition. The basketball team was reactivated in 1983 and continues to play. NYU currently has varsity teams in basketball, cross country, fencing, golf, soccer, swimming and diving, tennis, track and field, volleyball and wrestling. Baseball returned as a varsity sport in 2015 and softball was added as a result of NYU's completed merger with NYU-Poly.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access to audiovisual materials in this collection is available through digitized access copies. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room.
Related Materials
MC 78 Athletic Department Scrapbook
The University Archives Photo Collection contains images of NYU teams and players from the late 19th century into the 1980s. Late 19th and early 20th century athletics images can also be found in the Historic Photographs and Drawings Collection (PHOTO 002).
Scope and Contents
This collection is comprised of the records of athletics programs at New York University. It spans from 1889 to the 2000s and includes newspaper clippings, press releases, team statistics, rosters, schedules, program and player information related to a number of team and individual sports. The frequency of each type of record varies from series to series.
The bulk of the collection relates to basketball, football and baseball.
Additionally, RG 41.9 is not listed but is reserved for records pertaining to the University Athletic Association.
New York University -- Athletics; Soccer.; Basketball.; Fencing.; Baseball.; Gymnastics.; Football.; Nachamkin, Boris; Dyce, Byron; Coles, Jerome S.; Foley, Esther; Cann, Howard; DeCapriles, Miguel; Meehan, John; Quinn, Janice; McCarthy, William; Davis, George; Krowlikowski, Jen; Toussaint, Cheryl; DeCapriles, Jose; New York University; Csjaghy, Bela; Tanenbaum, Sidney
- RG 41.0: General athletics records, 1905-2009
  Scope and Contents
  This series touches on a wide array of subjects within NYU athletics. It includes sports and athletics program schedules, clippnigs, correspondence, and records relating to NYU Hall of Fame inductees Esther V. Foley and Albert B. Nixon. There are also copies of the athletics sections of The Violet, The Album, and the School of Education Violet yearbooks as well as records relating to the University Athletic Association and copies of "The Violet Line: The Official Newsletter of New York University Athletics".
  - 1945-1947 Sports Schedules, cuid2172 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1964-1965 Sports Schedules, cuid2173 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1965-1966 Sports Schedules, cuid2174 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1966-1967 Sports Schedules, cuid2175 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1967-1968 Sports Schedules, cuid2176 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1968-1969 Sports Schedules, cuid2177 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1969-1970 Sports Schedules, cuid2178 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1970-1971 Sports Schedules, cuid2179 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1971-1972 Sports Schedules, cuid2180 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1972-1973 Sports Schedules, cuid2181 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Open Spaces and Athletics Fall Courses 1976, cuid2182 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1977-1978 Sports Schedules and Athletics Course catalogue, cuid2183 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1978-1979 Sports Schedules, cuid2184 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1979-1980 Sports Schedules, cuid2185 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - The Jerome S. Coles Sports and Recreation Center 1981-1982 Procedures and Programs, cuid2186 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1982-1983 Sports Schedules, cuid2187 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 1983-1984 Sports Schedules, cuid2188 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 1985-1986 Sports Schedules and The Jerome S. Coles Sports and Recreation Center Information and Procedures, cuid2189 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 1986-1987 Sports Schedules, cuid2190 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Coles Program Guide 1987-1988, cuid2191 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Coles Program Guide 1988-1989, cuid2192 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 1994-1995 Sports Schedules, cuid2193 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Athletics Department Recreation Guide 2002-2003, cuid2194 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Faculty Family Day at Coles 2009 NYU vs. Emory, cuid2195 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - University of the City of New York Gymnasium "Prescription of Exercises" 19th Century, undated; cuid2196 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Esther V. Foley Papers 1929-1990, cuid2197 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Department of Athletics 1987-1988, cuid2198 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Press Clippings Athletic Department, circa 1970s, 2000; cuid2199 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Women's Athletics All Time Records 1871-1985, 1871-1958; cuid2200 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Women's Hall of Fame Records 1984 – as per M. Schlicting 1987, cuid2201 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Women's Hall of Fame Records 1980 – as per M. Schlicting 1987, cuid2202 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Women's Hall of Fame Records 1982 – as per M. Schlicting 1987, cuid2203 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Women's Hall of Fame Records 1983 – as per M. Schlicting 1987, cuid2204 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Women's Hall of Fame Records 1979 – as per M. Schlicting 1987, cuid2205 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Women's Hall of Fame Records 1978 – as per M. Schlicting 1987, cuid2206 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 1987 Hall of Fame Records, cuid2207 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Women's Hall of Fame Records 1986 – as per M. Schlicting 1987, cuid2208 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Albert B. Nixon Papers, 1932-1949; cuid2209 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Women's Basketball Press Clippings 1936, cuid2210 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - NYU Varsity Athletics Fundraising Proposal 1986, cuid2211 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Jerome S. Cole Sports and Recreation Center Dedication 1981, cuid2212 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Volleyball Women's Recruitment Information, Undated; cuid2213 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Women's Swimming Newspaper Clipping 1935, cuid2214 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Hall of Fame Inductees Newspaper Clippings of Nick Marino; Tom Casey; George Spitz; George Barker, Undated; cuid2215 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - AIDS Walk New York 2000, cuid2216 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Hall of Fame Dinner Mailer 2001, cuid2217 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Washington Square College and NYU Sports Bulletin Feb. 28,1938, 1938 28 February; cuid2218 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Athletic Yearbook Sections 1905-1906; 1909-1910, 1905-1910; cuid2219 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Commerce Violet – Athletics 1913-1914, cuid2220 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - The Violet Athletics 1913-1914, cuid2221 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - The Violet Athletics 1915-1916, 1916-1917, 1915-1917; cuid2222 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - The Violet Athletics 1925-1926, cuid2223 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - The Album Athletics 1925-1926, cuid2224 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Commerce Violet – Athletics 1915-1916, cuid2225 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Commerce Violet Athletics 1925-1926, 1934-1935, 1925-1935; cuid2226 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Commerce Violet Athletics 1937-1938, cuid2227 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - School of Education Athletics 1934-1935, cuid2228 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - The Violet Athletics 1934-1935, cuid2229 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - The Album Athletics 1937-1938, cuid2230 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - The Violet Athletics 1937-1938, cuid2231 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - School of Education Athletics 1949-1950, cuid2232 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - The Album Athletics 1949-1950, cuid2233 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - The Violet Athletics 1949- 1950, cuid2234 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Commerce Violet Athletics 1949-1950, cuid2235 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - The Violet Athletics 1950-1951, cuid2236 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Commerce Violet Athletics 1950-1951, cuid2237 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Education Athletics 1950-1951; 1954-1955, 1950-1955; cuid2238 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Violet Athletics 1954-1955, 1957-1958, 1954-1958; cuid2239 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Commerce Athletics 1954-1955, cuid2240 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Education Athletics 1957-1958, 1959-1960, 1957-1960; cuid2241 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Album Athletics 1950-1951, 1954-1955, 1950-1955; cuid2242 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Album Athletics 1957-1958, 1959-1960, 1957-1960; cuid2243 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Commerce Athletics 1957-1958, 1959-1960, 1957-1960; cuid2244 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Violet Athletics 1959-1960, cuid2245 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Album Athletics 1961-1962, 1966-1967, 1961-1967; cuid2246 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Commerce Athletics 1961-1962, 1966-1967, 1961-1967; cuid2247 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Education Athletics 1961-1962, 1966-1967, 1961-1967; cuid2248 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Violet Athletics 1961-1962, 1966-1967, 1961-1967; cuid2249 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Violet Athletics 1971-1972, cuid2250 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Education Athletics 1972-1973, cuid2251 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Torch Athletics 1974-1975, 1975-1976, 1976-1977, 1977-1978, 1979-1980,1981-1982, 1974-1982; cuid2252 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Torch Athletics 1982-1983, 1983-1984, 1984-1985, 1985-1986, 1986-1987, 1982-1987; cuid2253 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Torch Athletics 1987-1988, 1988-1989, 1989-1990, 1990-1991, 1991-1992, 1987-1992; cuid2254 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Education Athletics 1991-1992, cuid2255 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Torch Athletics 1992-1993, 1993-1994, 1997-1998, 1992-1998; cuid2256 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - 1957-1958 NYU Division of Athletics Information Guide, cuid2257 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 1987-1993 Misc. Promotional materials, cuid2258 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Coles Sports Center Membership Letter 1989-1990, cuid2259 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Intercollegiate Athletics Guide 1992-1993, cuid2260 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Athletics Guide 1982-1983, cuid2261 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - The Violet Line 1995-1996 "The Official Newsletter of New York University Athletics", cuid2262 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Violet Booster Club Brochure 2001-2002, cuid2263 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - University Athletic Association Memorial Golf Tournament Invite, 1990 30 March; cuid2264 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - University Athletic Association Papers, 1986-1987; cuid2265 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - University Athletic Association Papers 1994-1995, cuid2266 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Bobcat Shoes, cuid2268
  - Bobcat Costume, cuid2270
  - The Violet, flower costume, undated (Box 228, Box 230)
    ID Number: 148. Description: The Violet, flower costume.
  - Navy blue blazer with patch and two faded purple sweaters with NYU logo, undated (Box 231)
- RG 41.1: Basketball, 1906-1997
  History of Basketball at NYU
  Basketball has long presence at NYU. It began as an intra-school sport in 1897, only six years after the game was invented by Dr. James Naismith. Varsity competition began in 1906. The team, led by a student captain, won six of eight games the first year. Two years later the NYU Violets recorded their first undefeated season, winning all 13 games played. During the 1919-1920 season, the Violets achieved a 16-1 record and took part in the National Championship Tournament in Atlanta, where they won four straight games and became the National and World Champions. Howard Cann, who would go on to coach at NYU for 35 seasons, was voted the best player at that tournament. NYU teams would later practice in a gym on the University Heights campus made of two joined barns and nicknamed Cann's Barn.
  A decade later the Violets were playing at Madison Square Garden. Among the early stars of the team were All-American Hagan Anderson, Milt Schulman, Jerry Fleishman, Sid Tanenbaum, Don Forman, Dolph Schayes, Cal Ramsey, Tom "Satch" Sanders, Mal Graham, Barry Kramer, and Boris Nachamkin. These athletes led NYU into the NCAA Division I Championships five times between 1919 and 1960. The Violets were popular among the students, alumni, and the community, and the games were big sellers at Madison Square Garden.
  By the 1970s, the University was in a dire financial situation and cut the basketball program in an effort to balance the its budget. Following a gradual improvement in the school's financial standing, NYU reintroduced basketball in 1983 in Division III competition under Coach Mike Muzio.
  Women's basketball dates back to 1923. It was initially considered a "co-ed activity" until the 1930s, when it became a varsity sport. The University has had several winning teams since that time. Today the women's basketball team is one of the top teams at NYU and won the Division III Championship in 1997 with Coach Janice Quinn and players Marsha Harris and Jen Krolikowski.
  Series 41.1 includes newspaper clippings, basketball season schedules, photographs, tournament information, specific game and player breakdowns, official scorer's reports, pre-season rosters, coaches notes, player statistics, collected clippings, press information sheets, alumni basketball event correspondence, rosters, game souvenirs, season programs, brochures, tickets, retrospectives, and player biographies.
  Men's basketball results for 1906-2013 can be found in Archives H. Women's basketball results for 1923-2014 can be found in Archives H.
  - Encyclopedia of Basketball, 1906-1959 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Junior Varsity Basketball Schedule, 1946 January - 1947 March (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Women's Basketball Schedule, 1947 February - March 29 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - 1966 LOBO Invitation (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - 1959-1963 Basketball Clippings (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - 1966 National Invitation Tournament (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Basketball Clippings and Notes 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Basketball Clippings and Statistics 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - 1965 National Invitation Tournament Clippings (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - 1965-1966 Freshman Basketball (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - 1965-1966 Basketball Statistics, 1956-1966 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - 1931-1932 Basketball Squad (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - 1932-1933 Basketball Squad (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - 1933-1934 Basketball Squad (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - 1934-1935 Basketball Squad (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - 1935-1936 Basketball Squad (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - 1936-1937 Basketball Squad (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - 1937-1938 Basketball Squad (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - 1938-1939 Basketball Squad (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - 1939-1940 Basketball Squad (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Freshman Basketball 1940-1941, 1949-1950, 1940-1950 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - 1940-1941 Basketball Squad (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - 1941-1942 Basketball Squad (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - 1942-1943 Basketball Squad (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - 1943-1944 Basketball Squad (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - 1944-1945 Basketball Squad (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - 1945 Final Basketball Results (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - 1945-1946 Basketball Squad (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - 1946-1947 Basketball Squad (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Basketball Contracts, 1941-1951 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - 1947-1948 Basketball Squad (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - 1948-1949 Basketball Squad (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - 1949-1950 Basketball Squad (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - 1950-1951 Women's Basketball Squad (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - 1950-1951 Basketball Squad (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - 1951-1952 Women's Basketball Squad (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - 1951-1952 Basketball Squad (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - 1953-1954 Basketball Squad (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - 1954-1955 Basketball Squad (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 1955-1956 Basketball Squad (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - 1956-1957 Basketball Squad (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - 1957-1958 Basketball Squad (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - 1958-1959 Basketball Squad (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - 1959 National Invitation Tournament (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - 1952-1953 Basketball Squad (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - ECAC Holiday Festival, 1959-1967 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - 1959-1960 Basketball Squad (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - 1960-1961 Basketball Squad (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - 1960-1961 Freshman Basketball Squad (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - 1960 All College Tournament (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - 1961-1962 Basketball Squad (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - 1961-1962 Freshman Basketball Squad (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - 1962 NCAA Tournament (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - 1962-1963 Los Angeles Classic (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - 1962-1963 Basketball Squad (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - 1962-1963 Freshman Basketball Squad (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - 1963 NCAA Tournament (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - 1963-1964 Basketball Articles (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - 1963-1964 Freshman Basketball (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - 1963-1964 Basketball Squad (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - 1964-1965 National Invitation Tournament (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - 1964-1965 Freshman Basketball (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - 1964-1965 Basketball Squad Articles (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - 1964-1965 Basketball Squad (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - 1966-1967 Basketball Statistics (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - 1966-1967 Basketball Articles (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - 1966-1967 Basketball Squad (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - 1967 Hurricane Classics (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - 1967 Virginia VPI Tournament (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - 1966-1967 Freshman Basketball (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Alumni Cocktail Parties with Basketball Trips, 1966-1967 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - 1967-1968 Basketball Squad (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - 1967-1968 Basketball Clippings (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - 1968-1969 Basketball Squad (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - 1968-1969 Basketball Statistics (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - 1968-1969 Freshman Basketball (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - 1968-1969 Basketball Squad (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - 1967-1968 Alumni Gym Programs (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - 1967-1968 Freshman Basketball (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - 1967-1968 Basketball Statistics (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Press Release - Williams Appointed Coach, 1968 30 July (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Poinsetta Classic, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - NYU Cage Notes, 1968 5 December (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Marshall University Tournament, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - 1969-1970 Freshman Basketball (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - 18th Annual ECAC Holiday Festival, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - 1969-1970 Basketball News Releases (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - 1969-1970 Alumni Gym Programs (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - 1970 Basketball Clips (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - 1970 Basketball Final Stats (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - 1970 Rainbow Classic (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - 1970 Utah Classic (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - NCAA Stats 1970 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Basketball Final Statistics, Undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - 1970-1971 Basketball Press Releases (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - 1970-1971 Basketball Squad (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - 1969-1970 Basketball Squad (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - 1970-1971 Alumni Gym Programs (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - 1970-1971 Basketball Clips (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - 1970-1971 Freshman Basketball (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - 1970-1971 Basketball Opponents (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Lou Rossini Leaves NYU, 1971 18 March (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Elimination of the Basketball Program, 1971-1978 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - 1984-1986 Basketball (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - 1972 Club Basketball (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - 1992-1993 Basketball (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Women's Basketball Opponents, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - NCAA Women's Division III Championship, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Press Releases, 1934-1943 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Press Releases, 1943-1946 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Press Releases, 1946-1946 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Press Releases, 1946 - 1960 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Press Releases, 1960-1965 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Metropolitan Basketball Writers Association, 1934-1969 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Basketball Squad Roster, 1932-1933 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Basketball Squad Roster, 1933-1934 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - 1939 Basketball Record, 1938-1939 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Press Releases, 1958-1959 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Press Releases, 1959-1960 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Press Releases, 1960-1961 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Press Releases, 1961-1962 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Press Releases, 1962-1963 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Press Releases, 1963-1964 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Press Releases, 1964-1965 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Press Releases, 1965-1966 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Press Releases, 1966-1967 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Press Releases, 1967-1968 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Press Releases, 1968-1969 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Press Releases, 1969-1970 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Press Releases, 1970-1971 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Press Releases, 1971-1972 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Press Releases, 1983-1984 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Undated Press Release (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - 1912 Basketball Ticket, 1912 6 January (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Benefit Basketball Game Souvenir Program, 1930 22 Feb (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - 1940s Basketball Programs, 1945, 1948-1949 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Basketball Brochure, 1949-1950 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Basketball Brochures, 1950-1951, 1951-1952 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Basketball Brochures, 1955-1956 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Winter Sports Brochure, 1956-1957 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Basketball Yearbook, 1957-1958 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Winter Athletics Brochure, 1958-1959 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - 24th Annual All-College Brochure, 1959 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Basketball Brochure and Schedule, 1960-1961 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Basketball Brochure and Schedule, 1961-1962 (Box 16, Folder 12)